Hey friends, we're gonna talk a little bit about configuration.
嗨，朋友们，我们接下来谈一谈配置吧
But before we do, briefly I got an error before and I wanna fix that.
但是在做之前，我想先纠正一下之前的一个错误
And it was kind of annoying.
这有点烦人
I was goofing around here, if you look at our Razor, and this is incorrect.
如果你看一下 Razor 语句，我这样做其实并不对
I was being silly and goofing around, and when I was trying to do some math
当我尝试在 Razor 中计算时就会报错
inside of my Razor Page, cuz I'm experimenting
现在还没有什么好的解决方法
I kept getting this 500 error, this is the kind of error that you'd get in production.
一直得到错误代码为500的错误，这种错误在生产环境中经常会遇到
And it's annoying and it's scary, but it's not really helpful to me, is it?
这让人很讨厌，而且对我来说并没有什么帮助，是吧？
Well remember I'm running in production right now.
还好我意识到现在是在生产环境中运行的
Because over here in startup we said
因为在 Startup 这里我们说过
if environment is development show this developer exception page
如果是开发环境将会显示这个开发者调试页面
You're gonna show me later how to change from development to production
之后会讨论如何从开发环境转到生产环境
but I just wanted to briefly show that of course I can comment things out
但我想先简单地说一下这个事情
Just like before when we commented out starting a web app and instead changed it back to a console app.
就像以前一样，我们讨论的是一个 Web 应用，而不是控制台应用
What I want to do is make sure that this DeveloperExceptionPage You want to see it, right?
我想要做的是确保这个 DeveloperExceptionPage 能被看到，好嘛？
I want to see it, because I don't want a 500 error,I want a real error.
我想看到调试页面，而不是看到500错误，我想知道真正的错误
I want to know what's going on.
我想知道发生了什么事
So by removing that line you should be able to then see the mistake.
通过删除该行，应该是能够看到错误的
Right, now, the right thing to do is to switch to development mode
其实，正确的做法应该是切换到开发模式
but we are going to see that a little bit later okay?Now I'll go back here, I'm gonna hit refresh.
但我们稍后来讨论这点好吗？先回到这里，刷新
And now I'm getting a development page.
现在我获取了一个开发页面
You don't want to see this in production.
这些在开发环境中应该是不可见的
But it's showing me that well, this is not valid,this is not valid Razor, and it gives me the line of code.
它清楚地告诉了我这一行 Razor 代码是无效的
So now I actually know what's going on.
现在我终于知道发生什么了
And I'll go back over here.
回到这里
Could you go back to your home page?
能回到刚才的页面吗？
If you hit on the + button.
如果你在这点击 + 按钮
Okay, give me a little context of where it is in the page.
很好，我看到了它在页面中的一部分上下文
Because if it was thousands of lines,I might not know exactly where that was.
因为如果有千上万行的代码，我可能无法定位到它在哪里
-Good point, -all right.
-好主意 -当然喽
So instead of doing my 2+2 there,I am going to say @ and I gonna open a little block here.
所以, 不要在那计算 2+2 ，在这输入 @ 加上大括号
And we'll just make a variable like i,I'll do my 2+2 and then I will say i pm.
然后声明一个用于保存 2+2 的变量，再把这边改成 i pm
So if I made a mistake in here.
如果我在这里犯了一个错误
Forget to put the var.
故意忘记加入 var
It should give you an error.
应该会报错
It should say i does not exist and tell me the line.
它会说 i 并不存在，并告诉我错误在哪一行
So it's compiling that Razor Page the second that I hit refresh, all right?
在我点击刷新之后，它会重新编译 Razor 页面，是的吧？
-Interesting. -Good reminder.
-有趣 -很好的提示
It is a good reminder.
这是一个很友好的提示
So I'm just goofing around there.
警告我刚刚偷懒了
What we'll learn about a little bit later is how to set this environment so that it is in development
待会我们就学习怎么把环境设置为开发环境
so I don't have to comment that line out
那样也就不用把这一行注释掉了
So out of curiosity this isn't something that people would want to do in practice would they?
那为什么我们不在页面里就完成这部分计算呢？
Like by ejecting bits of C# everywhere into their code?
反正页面和后端都是用 C# 写的
Well it depends, that's good point.
问得好，这一点很重要
So we'll talk a little bit when we get a little further on the day about the responsibilities of a Razor Page
我们稍后再谈一点关于 Razor 页面的需求
vs the responsibilities of the page model or the code behind
以及页面模型或代码背后的需求
It is okay to do calculations in what's called the view
如果它们是基于视图
if they are view based calculations if they're stuff that's not business logic
而不是业务逻辑的话，在视图中进行也是可以的
For example,I don't think I would wanna calculate tax rates and shopping
例如，根据单一职责原则
for values in here from a responsibilities perspective
我不想在页面中计算税率和购买价值
But certainly I can chop up strings and do different kinds of
当然，我可以在这里加入一些
stuff so it is okay to inject little bits of C# in here.
例如用于分割字符串等功能的 C# 代码
It's more about is it gonna be maintainable for the rest of the team.
更重要的是它能够方便团队的其他成员维护
So we talked earlier, you had me talk about the difference between ConfigureServices and Configure.
所以我们早些时候谈过 ConfigureServices 和 Configure 之间的区别
I'm afraid we're going to insert another word that sounds like configure.
恐怕我们会使用另一个听起来像 configure 的词
I know, it's just like it's configuration, configure,configure it more, and configure it a little bit more.
我知道，听起来像是 configuration ，但 configure 用的多
That is software engineering, isn't it?
这就是软件工程，是吗？
It's mostly configuring things and running things.
它们主要掌管着配置和运行工作
Yeah, and they all have around the same names, so yeah.
是呀，他们的名字都很相像
So this module's configuration,what are we configuring in this context?
我们在模块配置这方面做了什么？
So I wanna show you how to add configuration into your application.
等会，我想告诉你如何将配置添加到应用程序中
That means like switches, options, things that you would,configuration for your app.
这有点像交换机，通过选项来为你的应用进行配置
That is different from setting up your services.
但这跟设置服务是不同的
-Exactly -Okay, all right.
-确实 -好的
So if you open up, are we in Startup?
你打开了嘛，我们是在 Startup 文件中嘛？
We are in startup.
是的
-Yes, we are -We call it Beyonce,which is probably gonna confuse people.
-好的 - 我们叫它 Beyonce，这听起来是不是怪怪的
I know, should we still call it Beyonce?
也是哈，那我们还叫它 Beyonce 吗？
We should probably change it back to startup because we don't want to lose our jobs.
我们还是把它改回去吧，我们可不能因为这个出差错
Let's just change it back to startup.
让我们把它改回去
Okay, we're in the Startup class.
还是 Startup 类
Cool, and we want to pull information out of a config file.
酷，我要从配置文件中获取信息
-Yes we do -Where is the config file?
-来吧 -配置文件在哪里？
In IConfiguration.
在 IConfiguration 这儿
Yeah but the name, the file itself, the settings for the application.
我说的是这应用程序程序的配置文件的名称
You actually have to add, you mean you add your app json?
你要往你的的应用程序中添加 json ？
Is that what you're looking for?
要不然是在找什么？
Your app settings right, so let's do that first.
若你的应用设置正确的话，就让我们开始吧
So appsettings.json.
appsettings.json
That's the default name for settings for your app.
这是应用设置的默认名称
Now I can put anything in here right,as long as it's json it's totally up
现在我可以把任何东西放在这里，只要它是json就可以了
无论我想要的配置信息是什么
whatever configuration information I want right?
So we'll have like some message.
我们会收到一些消息
Yeah it can be like friendly call from Beehive or hello from.
它从 Beehive 获知 Hello 的友好消息
Yeah, here's a greeting.
这是一个问候
From the config
在配置里
And you're configuration it really can be anything that is application specific,any name value pair.
你可以把它配置为任意的一个名字
Exactly, so you could have logging over there as well,could you not?
你也可以在别处看到这个信息对吗？
Yeah, we'll see a little bit later we'll have the logging levels.
可以，稍后我们会看到我们的日志系统
It can be, there'll be a place to put connection strings and all kind of stuff.
它可能会有一个放置连接字符串等数据的地方
And we'll talk about the differences between where user secrets go
我们将讨论用户隐私数据
where connection strings go and where non secret things go
字符串连接和公开数据的异同
So just for reference for people who are going to be watching this
因此，给你们一点参考
when I've been using the app settings I've been using it mainly for configuration of my database
我配置数据库的时候都会以此进行应用程序设置
Okay, so it depends on whether the configuration for your database is a secret.
好的，这取决于数据库的配置是否是机密
It's a secret.
这是一个机密
-Or not -It should be a secret.
它应该是一个秘密
It should not have been there,do not do this, although it's defaulted in the template.
它不应该把你的连接字符串放在那里，尽管它在模板中是默认的
-But as someone -Well let's take a look at the template.
但是有人... - 让我们来看看模板
But as someone who has put apps into production
但是，作为将应用程序投入使用环境的人员
what are some of the most common things that you have actually used something like this for?
实际上使用类似这样的东西的一些最常见的事情是什么？
So let's say maybe like someone's email address
因此，让我们假设为别人的电子邮件地址
or I might have if I'm writing a blog number of posts on homepage, ten, whatever.
或者正在博客的主页上撰写帖子
It could be anything that is a quick little switch or change that you might want to pop in a config file and update.
在任何你需要配置的文件中它可以是一个快捷的开关或更改方式
And what's nice aboutconfiguration as it's configurable
关于配置的话，因为我们使用的是 json，所以配置起来很方便
we're using json it could be an ini file,it could be an XML file
它可以是 ini 文件，也可以是一个 XML 文件
It could be a database somewhere.
它也可以是某处的数据库
Any of the kinds of options that you want show ads on the homepage.
任何类型的选项都可以，比如你想在首页展示广告的话
I was just thinking about things that I do on my blog,that kind of stuff.
或者说在博客上添加一些自定义的内容
Cuz I think people see and they just what is that about and they think it's important to understand
因为我想人们看见就会去想这到底是什么，是否便于理解就非常重要
Showing Messages is a silly kind of generic kind of thing.
用 Messages 这些形式就很不友好
Like these are some real world examples.
这些是现实生活中的一些真实的情况
Yeah, like if you were having paging, PageSize before I hit next, next or whatever.
是的，如果你要设置分页，可以用 PageSize 设置每一页的数量
So if I have 100 blogs post,maybe my PageSize is gonna be 10.
如果我有100个博客发布，也许我的 PageSize 将是10
These are the kinds of things you wanna have in a config file somewhere that you can then pull out in your code.
你可以通过代码获得你想要从配置文件中得到的数据
So we're gonna figure out how to pull that out, all right.
我们要弄清楚如何解决读取配置，是吧
So let's go back to startup and configuration is a service.
所以让我们回到 Startup ，配置信息也是一项服务
It's a thing like logging is a service, you had MVC as a service
它就像日志、 MVC 一样是服务
so we need to make sure that we can inject that service
所以我们需要确保注入了这项服务
That's a dependency that we're gonna inject into our system okay.
这是我们要注入系统的依赖
Dependency injection how much do you wanna talk about that?
你想谈谈依赖注入吗？
I'm going to talk about that a little bit more in a different one.
我会在另一章中再探讨这个话题
So for now we will just assume that
我们会在稍后深入研究
we'll give you a little bit of background before we get deeper into it later
在这之前先了解一下基础知识吧
So I'm gonna just make a constructor, right,my Startup constructor here.
我会在这里创建一个构造函数，我的 Startup 类的构造函数
And whatever parameters the startup constructor has will be
无论 Startup 的构成函数需要什么参数
given to me automatically by the system.
系统都会自动为构造函数提供参数
They'll be injected directly to the system.
他们将直接注入其中
So I need the ability to have an IConfiguration, and this is a little trickier, let's watch this very careful.
所以我需要有 IConfiguration ，这有点棘手，让我们仔细观察一下
I'm gonna type IConfiguration, and at the end of it,see it how it's all squiggly.
我输入 IConfiguration ，并在最后看到它产生怎同样的变化
-Yeah -I'm gonna hit Ctrl+dot.
-嗯嗯 -按下 Ctrl + .
And it gives you the options.
这里出现了一些选择
And it says, well, do you make one of these?
它是在说，这里面有你想要的吗?小伙子~
Or is it the one, do you mean this one here?
你是说这个，还是那个？
We mean that one there.
我们指的是那个
Right, and there's actually two options.
对，实际上有两种选择
You can add the using statement.
你可以添加使用语句
Or fully express it almost like a path like C:/, whatever, whatever, whatever.
或者通过这种像 C:/ 的绝对路径的方式来直接使用了
It's that full path, to IConfiguration.
这就是 IConfiguration 的完整路径
That wouldn't make it available to the entire program.
但这不会使整个程序都可用
And we'd have to do that every single time we used it.
我们每次使用它都必须这样做
-Yeah. -Exactly, good point.
是啊 - 好的，那就这样吧
So we'll say using, and then watch up here on line 8, so watch at line 8.
我们来添加 using ，然后注意看着第八行
Ta-da, yeah.
塔达，是的
So it just drops in there automatically.
它会自动添加到哪里
So Startup, our Startup class, is gonna need IConfiguration,and we can call it whatever, call config.
Startup，我们的 Startup 类需要 IConfiguration ，我们可以调用它来配置
And then we're gonna store it away,cuz they're gonna pass it in to us, they're gonna make one.
然后我们会把它储存起来，因为它会在这里传给我们一个对象
And this is important, we'll talk about dependency injection later
这很重要，我们稍后会讨论依赖注入
but the part that you need to remember is that you don't need to make one, you just ask for it
但是你记住你不需要创建一个新的对象，你只需要用它就可以了
And by asking for it, we put it in as a parameter.
把它作为一个参数来使用它
So we don't actually go and say new, whatever.
我们实际上并不会去新建一个对象
So I'll say public IConfiguration,and we can name it Configuration.
接着创建一个公开的 IConfiguration ，我们可以将其命名为 Configuration
-Yeah. -And this is gonna be a property.
-是啊 -这是一个属性
Yeah, so have a get and a set.
是的，所以需要 get 和 set 方法
Get in the set, excellent.
get 和 set ，完美
And then, we just squirrel it away as they say.
然后，我们把参数 config 的值赋值给 Configuration
Configuration = config.
Configuration = config
So they pass it in when we start up
当我们启动 Startup 类的时候
and we stick it over here,which then presumably means I can use it, right?
就意味着我们可以使用 Configuration，对吧？
Yes, you can so you should be able to use it right from your page.
是的，你可以在任何页面中都可以使用它
I can use it wherever.
任何地方
It should be setting around, so I could be down here
在这里进行配置
I was gonna say this.Configuration and then those are all the things one can do.
键入 this.Configuration 这些就是我们可以做的事
Now that is within my C# application.
现在在我的 C＃ 应用程序中
My C# code, my Startup.cs
我的 C＃ 代码，我的 Startup.cs
but if we go back over here, let's go to our index one, our Beyonce RAZOR PAGE
但如果我们回到这里，到我们的 Beyonce Razor 页面
You said I can use it from within here directly.
你说我可以直接在这里使用它
Yes, but we need to inject it first.
是的，但我们需要先注入它
Okay, so just like it was, inject it in,it was made available.
好吧，就像这样，注入它，就可以使用了
Mm-hm.
嗯
Inject is kind of an intense word.
注入是一个听起来很牛的词
I know.
我知道
I asked for it, and they gave it to me.
我发起请求，然后就能得到它
I think eject is a little intense, but-Please.
我认为直接弹出会有点不合适，但 - 没关系
So I'll say h2, h2.
先加入一个 的标签
No, can I say @Config?
我可以输入 @Config 吗？
Can I just go and say, Config?
我能直接输入 Config ?
Yes you can, @Config would, yeah.
可以呀，用 @Config 就可以
But I can't, because it hasn't been injected yet.
但是我不能，因为它还没有被注入
No, you actually have to have @inject Configuration.
不，你实际上必须有 @inject Configuration
Okay, so up here where it says @page
好的，在上方这里有一个 @page
Yeah,you need a new directive.
是的，你需要一个新的指令
I need another directive, I need to go inject, okay?
我需要另一个指令，来进行注入，对吗？
And then, when I say IConfiguration, though,it's not gonna work.
当我输入 IConfiguration 时，它没有奏效
Yeah, because we can still need to inject the using statement.
是的，因为我们仍然需要注入使用语句
We have to add the using statement, so using and a bit later on
我们必须添加使用语句，以便稍后使用
we'll see how to do this for every page, instead of having to do it on one page, but I'm gonna say using.
我们将看到如何为每个页面执行此操作，而不必在每一页上完成
Then I will say inject IConfigaration,and we will just call it Configuration.
然后我会注入 IConfigaration ，叫它 Configuration
So this is asking for it.
这用来充当请求
-Yes. -Okay, and then down here, I could say Configuration
-是的 -好吧，然后在这里，我可以输入 @Configuration
and we called it We called a whole bunch of things.
然后可以调用这所有的东西
We say message.
比如说 Message
-Okay. -Message.
-好的 -那就 Message 吧
Cuz it's just a bag, a bag of stuff.
因为它只是一个包，一包数据
Oops, I can do it on multiple lines, I'll do it on one line.
哎呀，我可以一行上完成，不用占这么多行
All right, let's see if that breaks.
好吧，让我们看看是否会报错
That's my positive attitude speaking.
讲真我还是很乐观的
-Keeping it real. -Yeah, let's see if that breaks,that's the attitude of the developer.
-让事实说话吧 - 好，让我们看看这是否能运行，这是开发者一定要做的
I think it'll be okay.
我认为这没有问题
-Breaking things is fun, then you get to fix them, right? -That is true.
-中断让事情变得有趣，然后你就可以解决它们，对吧？-确实是的
So that's our Solange page, let's look at our home page
所以这就是我们的 Solange 页面，让我们看看我们的主页
here it go, here's a greeting from the config file.
在这里，这些数据可是来自配置文件的
Let's go back and change that.
让我们回去变一下
-To another greeting? -Yeah.
-改成别的值吗？-是啊
All right, so that's coming out of that config file,we changed the config file
好吧，数据是由配置文件设定的，我们更改了配置文件
and the value changed,we did not change the code, all right?
数据就会发生变化，我们可是没有更改代码，对吗？
-Yeah -That's pretty cool.
-对 -这很酷
It's worth pointing out a couple of things, though.
不过，值得指出一些事情
First, we have a using statement in our RAZOR PAGE,just like we did over in our CS.
首先，我们在 RAZOR 页面中有一个使用声明，就像我们在 C# 中所做的一样
I wonder.
我在想
Could I do this?
我可以这样做吗？
-It should be a dot, right?
-它应该是一个点，对吧？
-Right, thank you.
-对，谢谢
So fully qualified path, yes -It worked.
所以完整路径也是可行的 - 是的
Well, it worked and that it didn't break
它在正常运行，并没有受影响
Okay, it worked.
好的，运行正常
-Alright -Yeah, it worked in quotes.
-好吧 -嗯，一切正常
So that's interesting, I can back out of that, and then I later on
这很有趣，我可以退出来
we'll see how we could make that configuration available ever with.
然后我会看到我们如何使配置可用
-Yes. -Cuz I don't wanna have to keep adding.
-是 -因为我不得不继续添加
Cuz always could have to add it to every single page that you have.
总是可以将其添加到您拥有的每一个页面中
Yeah, I have got three lines of directives here and we got two lines of HTML, so that's real fun.
是的，我在这里有三行指令，我们有两行 HTML ，所以这真的很有趣
-Yeah. -Okay, so I think we'll take a break and then we'll graduate to Visual Studio Proper.
-是啊 -好吧，让我们休息一下，然后我们将开始正确地使用 Visual Studio
Yes, we are. -Very cool.
-是的 -很酷